# **Zheng Zixiang**

Address: 134 Simei Street 1, Singapore 520134 Street 1 · Phone: +6593285809

Email: Zixiangzann@gmail.com

### **Profile**

8+ years of experience in Software Quality Assurance with full system development lifecycle experience. Experience in designing, planning, and executing Testcases, test strategy and Software automation to ensure quality testing activities and product up to client standard.

#### **Software Skills**

Design and project documentation: Adobe Photoshop, Gimp, MS Office

 Software development and Automation tools: Java, Python, SQL, Autoit, Appium, JS, JMeter, Postman, Robot Framework

Data Analytics skills and tools: Python, Tableau, Excel, R, SQL

Operating Systems : Windows 10, Mac, Android

Databases : SQL ServerBug Tracking Tools : Jira, Excel

#### **Achievements**

- Knowledgeable in Test Automation Tools (Selenium, Autoit, JMeter, Postman, Appium, Robot Framework).
- Perform Manual Testing and maintain documentation on different types of testing like Positive, Negative, Functional, Regression, Sanity and System Testing.
- Prepare Test Cases and Test procedures based on Business Requirements Document and executed them accordingly.
- Assist in defect call meetings to discuss status of high severity issues.
- Experience in Jira Defect Tracking Tool.
- Participate actively in the Requirement review meetings, Team meetings, to discuss the possible scenarios of testing.
- Interact with the development team to test the bugs once they were fixed.
- Perform Positive and Negative Testing to ensure requirements were met.
- Coordinate actively with technical peers, such as Developers, Project Managers, and Business/User groups.
- Collaborated with testing and development team to achieve quality product after testing.

#### Education

- Certificate in Automation Test Engineer(Simplilearn's Master Program) simplilearn (April 2022)
- Certificate in Data Analyst (Simplilearn's Master Program)
  Simplilearn (OCT 2021)
  - Certifications in Java PROGRAMMING (Basic to Advanced)
     G-TEC COMPUTER EDUCATION CENTRE (March2018)

## • Diploma in culinary

At-Sunrice GlobalChef Academy (January 2012-May 2013)

## **Professional Experience**

# Elixir Technology Pte. Ltd.

Role: Software Quality Assurance Engineer [Sep 2019 - Present]

Web development for JTC J-Space

- Quality assurance, ensure quality and software meets planned functionality.
- Collect requirement from client, sync with Developer and write project documentation.
- Design, plan and execute Testcases and test strategy.
- Design, plan and build Web automation testing with Java Selenium.
- Prioritizing, planning and coordinating quality testing activities.
- Create UI Change Mock-up and collect feedback from client to make the necessary changes before making the actual changes.
- Support Client for any change request

# **Pactera Singapore Pte Ltd**

Role: Software Test Assistance Engineer [Jul 2013 - Sep 2019]

Quality assurance for Razer Gaming Product

### **Actions/Responsibilities**

- Adherence to Software Test Life Cycle and Defect Life Cycle Management.
- Design, plan and execute Testcases and test strategy.
- Preparing defect report as per severity and priority.
- Design, plan and build Windows automation testing with Autoit.
- Engage with Manager for man power planning based on client project plans.
- Work on improvement to improve overall operation.
- Assist on efficient cost managing.
- Evaluate and appraise team performance.
- Collect requirement from client, sync with Developer and write project documentation.
- Design, plan and execute Testcases and test strategy.